<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Developer Setup on Mattermost Developers</title>
    <link>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Developer Setup on Mattermost Developers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 11:35:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Apps Workflow</title>
      <link>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/developer-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/developer-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Running and Building the Apps Use the Makefile commands to run and build the apps. See these instructions for developing on a real device.
Adding New Dependencies to the Project If you need to add a new dependency to the project, it is important to add them in the right way. Instructions for adding different types of dependencies are described below.
JavaScript Only If you need to add a new JavaScript dependency that is not related to React Native, use npm, not yarn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makefile Commands</title>
      <link>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/makefile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/makefile/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve included a bunch of make commands in order to control the development flow and to ensure that everything works as expected. Always try and use these make commands unless they can&amp;rsquo;t accomplish what you need to do.
Every make command has to be run from a terminal in the project&amp;rsquo;s root directory. Try running make help to get a short description in your terminal about every make command available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run on a Device</title>
      <link>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/run-on-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/run-on-device/</guid>
      <description>If you want to test the app or if you want to make a contribution it is always a good idea to run the app on an actual device. This will let you ensure that the app is working correctly and in a performant way before making a pull request.
Running on Android Devices Enable Debugging over USB Most Android devices can only install and run apps downloaded from Google Play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 11:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contribute/mobile/developer-setup/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Errors When Running &amp;lsquo;make run-android&amp;rsquo; Error message React-native-vector-icons: cannot find dependencies Solution Make sure the Extras &amp;gt; Android Support Repository package is installed with the Android SDK.
Error message Execution failed for task &amp;#39;:app:packageAllDebugClassesForMultiDex&amp;#39;. &amp;gt; java.util.zip.ZipException: duplicate entry: android/support/v7/appcompat/R$anim.class Solution Clean the Android part of the mattermost-mobile project. Issue the following commands:
 cd android ./gradlew clean  Error message Execution failed for task &amp;#39;:app:installDebug&amp;#39;. &amp;gt; com.android.builder.testing.api.DeviceException: com.android.ddmlib.InstallException: Failed to finalize session : INSTALL_FAILED_UPDATE_INCOMPATIBLE: Package com.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>